
/*  PHP Quiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers 
 */

let questions = [

/* Q1 */     
	{
      numb: 1,
      question: "PHP stands for",
      options: [
                "A) Hypertext Preprocessor",
                "B) Pretext Hypertext Preprocessor",
                "C) Personal Home Processor",
                "D) None of the above"
               ],
      answer: "A) Hypertext Preprocessor"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q2 */     
	{
      numb: 2,
      question: "Who is known as the father of PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) Drek Kolkevi",
                "B) List Barely",
                "C) Rasmus Lerdrof",
                "D) None of the above"
               ],
      answer: "C) Rasmus Lerdrof"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q3 */     
	{
      numb: 3,
      question: "Variable name in PHP starts with -",
      options: [
                "A) ! (Exclamation)",
                "B) $ (Dollar)",
                "C) & (Ampersand)",
                "D) # (Hash)"
               ],
      answer: "B) $ (Dollar)"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q4 */     
	{
      numb: 4,
      question: "Which of the following is not a variable scope in PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) Extern",
                "B) Local",
                "C) Static",
                "D) Global"
               ],
      answer: "A) Extern"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q5 */     
	{
      numb: 5,
      question: "Which of the following is correct to add a comment in php?",
      options: [
                "A) & .... &",
                "B) // ....",
                "C) /* .... */",
                "D) Both (b) and (c)"
               ],
      answer: "D) Both (b) and (c)"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
	{
      numb: 6,
      question: " Which of the following is used to display the output in PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) echo",
                "B) write",
                "C) print",
                "D) Both (a) and (c)"
               ],
      answer: "D) Both (a) and (c)"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
	{
      numb: 7,
      question: "Which of the following is used for concatenation in PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) + (plus)",
                "B) * (Asterisk)",
                "C) . (dot)",
                "D) append()"
               ],
      answer: "C) . (dot)"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
	{
      numb: 8,
      question: "Which of the following starts with __ (double underscore) in PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) Inbuilt constants",
                "B) User-defined constants",
                "C) Magic constants",
                "D) Default constants"
               ],
      answer: "C) Magic constants"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
	{
      numb: 9,
      question: "Which of the following is the correct way of defining a variable in PHP?",
      options: [
                "A) $variable name = value",
                "B) $variable_name = value;",
                "C) $variable_name = value",
                "D) $variable name as value"
               ],
      answer: "B) $variable_name = value;"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
	{
      numb: 10,
      question: "Which of the following function displays the information about PHP and its configuration?",
      options: [
                "A) php_info()",
                "B) phpinfo()",
                "C) info()",
                "D) None of the above"
               ],
      answer: "B) phpinfo()"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


]; /* Array close*/